{"questions":[{"question":"In which of the following modes, transmission errors are not propagated?","answer":"Output Feedback Mode"},{"question":"Select the modes in which computations do not depend on outputs from previous stages","answer":"Electronic Code Book"},{"question":"Which among the following is an active attack?","answer":"User Impersonation"},{"question":"The computational complexity of __________ problem is exploited by Diffie_Hellman algorithm","answer":"Discrete Logarithm"},{"question":"Which among the following are steps in each round of AES algorithm?","answer":"Substitute Bytes"},{"question":"What is the size of the hash value produced by MD5 algorithm?","answer":"128 bits"},{"question":"Which among the following is the most desirable property to enhance the computational complexity of cryptosystems?","answer":"Key size"},{"question":"The size of the output produced by hash functions is __________","answer":"Fixed based on the hash algorithm"},{"question":"Frequency analysis can be performed on polyalphabetic ciphers which makes it weak.","answer":"True"},{"question":"The idea behind “confusion” in cryptography is to hide the relationship between the plaintext and ciphertext.","answer":"False"},{"question":"Which among the following best describes hash collision attack?","answer":"Different input strings, same hash result"},{"question":"Which among the following may be addressed using message authentication?","answer":"All the options"},{"question":"The number of keys used in Triple DES algorithm:","answer":"2 or 3"},{"question":"Based on the network security protocols, which of the following algorithms are used to generate message digests?","answer":"MD5"},{"question":"The primary goal of cryptanalysis is to __________","answer":"Find the insecurities of the cryptosystem"},{"question":"Digital Signature is implemented using__________","answer":"Public key system"},{"question":"Which among the following algorithms is designed based on the Feistel Cipher?","answer":"DES"},{"question":"The cryptographic method that is considered to be truly unbreakable:","answer":"One-time pad"},{"question":"Kerchkoff’s principle emphasizes that the cryptosystem should be accessible to the adversary without inconvenience:","answer":"True"},{"question":"The hash function value used in message authentication is also known as _________","answer":"Message Digest"},{"question":"Which of the following is widely used in cryptography to create a trapdoor function to facilitate exchange of keys?","answer":"Factorization"},{"question":"The uses of hashing algorithms include:","answer":"All the options"},{"question":"Diffie-Hellman algorithm is applicable for exchange of keys between two parties only.","answer":"False"},{"question":"Which among the following is the most resistant to frequency analysis?","answer":"Beaufort"},{"question":"Which of the following cryptographic strategy may be used to overcome Man-in the Middle attacks?","answer":"Authentication"},{"question":"In digital cryptography, each character is represented as__________","answer":"12 bits X"}]}